thewatchhut.co.uk 2016-11-22

# Security & Privacy

### SECURITY & PRIVACY

### PRIVACY POLICY

TheWatchHut.co.uk (TWH) ("We") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out how we will and will not use the personal information you give use so please read the following carefully. By visiting TheWatchHut.co.uk (our site) you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Watchshop Ltd T/A The Watch Hut, Aurum House, 2, Elland Road, Leicester, LE3 1TT

### INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

When you shop with us you will submit your personal information to us. We will treat all information submitted by you in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy and in strict compliance with all Data Protection legislation. By entering your personal information on one or more of our sites you accept that we may retain your information and it may be held by us or by any third party company that processes it on our behalf. 

When you shop with us we may collect and process the following data about you:

### INFORMATION YOU GIVE US

Information that you provide by filling in forms on our sites including information provided when you search for and/or order products, subscribe to any services we offer, request further services, comment on our blogs, submit any product reviews, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on our site, enter competitions, promotions or surveys. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our site. If you contact us, we may keep a record of the correspondence.

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

On each visit to our sites we may automatically collect the following information:

  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders. This means that we can deal quickly with any problems you may experience with your order;
  * Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access;
  * Calls made to our customer services department may be recorded for monitoring and quality control purposes;
  * We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to collate aggregate information. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.  

### INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM OTHER SOURCES

We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

### COOKIES

Our sites use cookies to distinguish you from other users helping us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our sites and allowing us to improve our site. For more information on the cookies we use and what we use them for see our [cookie policy.](http://www/) 

### USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We use information held about you in the following ways:

### INFORMATION YOU GIVE TO US

We will use this information:

  * To deal with your orders for the supply of our goods;
  * To provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
  * To provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you.
  * If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data;  

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

We will use this information:

  * To administer our sites and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * To improve our sites to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer or device;
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * As part of our efforts to keep our sites safe and secure;
  * To measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
  * To make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our sites about goods or services that may interest you or them;  

### INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM OTHER SOURCES

We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006. We may also share your information with selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with (them or) you;
  * Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 750 men aged under 55 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in RG9). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience;
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.  

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * If we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * If TWH or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of TWH, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.  

### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

SECURITY

We take your security and privacy very seriously, and do everything we can to keep the details of your order and payment secure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.

We use Internet standard encryption technology to scramble your data after you transmit it to us. This process is known as SSL (secure sockets layer).

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our sites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet may not be completely secure. However, once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to protect your personal data.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [customerservices@thewatchhut.co.uk](mailto:customerservices@thewatchhut.co.uk).

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from websites of our advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that they have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to customerservices@thewatchhut.co.uk.

COOKIE POLICY

### INFORMATION ABOUT OUR USE OF COOKIES

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. We use the following cookies: 

### STRICTLY NECESSARY COOKIES.

These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, or use the shopping cart.

### ANALYTICAL/PERFORMANCE COOKIES.

They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

### FUNCTIONALITY COOKIES.

These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences.

### TARGETING COOKIES.

These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

### Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. 

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.
